<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install &amp; configuration</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</guid>
      <description>This guide will walk you through the process of installing and configuring reef-pi on a Raspberry Pi. The entire installation process involves three main stages.
 Creating a MicroSD card for Raspberry Pi Starting Raspberry Pi and configuring it to be used with reef-pi Install and configuration of reef-pi on the Raspberry Pi  This guide assumes prior familiarity with computers, no programming knowledge is required.
Prepare Raspberry Pi image We recommend a microSD card of Class10 and at least 8Gb capacity for reef-pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Check if reef-pi is running  sudo systemctl status reef-pi.service   Check for errors in log  sudo journalctl -fu reef-pi.service   Connecting reef-pi using a TTL cable. Adafruit has an excellent tutorial on how to use USB TTL cable to configure raspberry pi, in cases where display and keyboard is not available.
 Check reef-pi version (helps in bug reports)
  reef-pi -version   Resetting reef-pi &amp;rsquo;s data base  sudo systemctl stop reef-pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</guid>
      <description>Automated power strips allow on-demand and timer based control of AC outlets (110v or 220v). They are one of the easiest to build yet most useful controllers using reef-pi. For example, a power controller can turn on/off light or skimmer daily as well as allow on-demand controls like switching off ATO and return pump during water changes. This guide will go through step by step process of building a four outlet power controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</guid>
      <description>There are times when you want to get your Raspberry Pi up and running completely headlessly. Maybe you typically use a laptop and don&amp;rsquo;t have an extra keyboard. Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way to connect to an HDMI monitor. This guide will show you how you to set up your Pi to be completely headless. This will allow your Pi to connect to your wireless network and connect via SSH on its first boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</guid>
      <description>Lighting is one of the key aspects of a maintaining a thriving reef tank. Most corals in reef tanks are photosynthetic and require lighting from a specific spectrum (400-700 nm). Different corals prefer different intensities of lighting for their optimal growth; these are generally specified in PAR (photosynthetically active radiation) values. For example, acropora species prefer higher PARs (250 and above) while acan and mushroom species prefer lower PARs (less than 150).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Determine appropriate reef-pi version based on raspberry pi (3 or zero) from the release page. Choose latest relase if you are unsure. For this documentation we&amp;rsquo;ll use 1.0 release version on pi zero.
 Open a terminal window using the ssh software of your choices. SSH into your raspberry pi, then login into reef-pi and upgrade by entering the following commands in the terminal window
 Download the release package on reef-pi (remember to use the correct pi-x.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiring and connectors</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</guid>
      <description> Connectors  3.5 mm right angle, male audio jacks with bare wire 3.5 mm female panel mount audio jack DC female panel mount barel jack 5 volt 2.5 amp micro USB power supply 12 volt, 1 amp DC barrel jack power supply  Wiring  Breadbord Perf board Perma proto board  Configuring reef-pi Pin number in outlets represent GPIO number.
References  Sparkfun article on connectors  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill of Materials</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/bom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/bom/</guid>
      <description> Raspberry Pi 3 MicroSD card 5 volt 2.5 A power supply Female jumper wires PCA9685 breakout board DS18B20 temperature probe Photo electric water level sensor 2N3904 Transistor 4.7k resistor Two 10k resistors Two 1K resistors Standoffs 12v power adapter lm2596 voltage regulators  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Access</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</guid>
      <description>This guide meant to assist in establishing a remote connection to your reef-pi main control page using one of the two popular options, RealVNC and Tor. reef-pi is normally accessible only within the home wifi network, using any of these two approaches you can access reef-pi from anywhere.
RealVNC The first option is to use software such as Real VNC. They offer a cloud option that will allow you to access your Raspberry Pi from anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Top Off</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</guid>
      <description>Automatic top off units are systems that maintain a constant water volume inside a reef tank. Reef tanks undergoe water evaporation which results in loss of water volume, which in turn increases the salinity of remaining water. Corals are highly sensitive to salinity thus unless the evaporated water is supplemented with fresh RO/DI water it will have a detrimental effect to corals. Auto top off units monitors water level periodically and when it falls below a certain level, they switch on an ATO pump to replenish the lost water volume with fresh RO/DI water, till it reaches the expected volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</guid>
      <description>Maintain stable temperature is a key requirement for a thriving reef tank. Most reef tanks maintain a stable temperature within 77 to 80 degree fahrenheit for optimal coral growth. Depending upon the environment where reef tank is located this might require cooling down the tank using a chiller or heating it up with a heater. Because environmental temperature varies during day and night at most places, reef tank temperature is often monitored and controlled automatically using a controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</guid>
      <description>Building an appropriate housing is a critical part of a controller build. Housing or enclosure secures the electronics from outside environment, as well as provides a mounting place for the different probes, equipment and display panels.
Housing material Depending upon where and what type of controller you are building you can use 3d-printed or wooden or out of the shelf plastic of metal enclosures. I personally use plywood since its easy to cut in pieces and all the material required are readily available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi installation and configuration  HDMI cable and monitor or TV USB based keyboard and mouse USB TTL Cable A computer with SD card reader  Wiring and testing electronics  soldering iron, solder, faux etc. plier wire stripper Screw driver (philips, m8 etc) multimeter  Wood working  Dremel or some other rotary tools Scroll saw Clamps  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</guid>
      <description>0-10v A method of diming leds using voltage.
3.5mm right angle, female panel mount audio jack A mini audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
3.5mm right angle, bare wire male audio connector A mini right angle audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
5 volt 2.5 amp micro USD power supply A power supply that will provide ample power for a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/telemetry/</guid>
      <description> Signing up for adafruit.io account Configuring reef-pi with adafruit.io key </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camera controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/camera/</guid>
      <description>The camera controller provides easy and convenient way to take reef tank photos on demand and at periodic intervals. reef-pi can also be configured to upload the images taken to google drive. This is useful when users are far from the tank for longer periods (like in vacation), the uploaded images can provide an easy way to stay up to date with current state of the tank. The camera controller does not involve any other electronics other than the official camera module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touchscreen display</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/display/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/display/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi can be configured to be used with the offical Raspberry Pi Touchscreen display to provide a direct access to reef-pi, without any network dependency. With a touchscreen it is possible to run reef-pi without any internet or even home wifi connection ( albeit modules like telemetry will not work). Activities like equipment on/off during water change, light intensity controls are all possible with touchscreen. Workflows involving editing text (like the one involved in creating new timer or equipment) are harder to setup, but can be done using on screen keyboard software (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development environment</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi is written in go and react. This guide will walk through the steps involved in setting up go and nodejs (required for react) development environment, alongside reef-pi. This guide assume OSX or Linux as the development platform.
Setup go reef-pi is built and tested with latest go. At the time of writing the guide, the latest version of go is 1.8.1. reef-pi should work with any version of go above 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi porvides a simple HTTP JSON based Application Programming Interface. reef-pi web user interface itself is built using this API. API can be used to control reef-pi from an external system as well. Following is the reef-pi 1.0 API which will not have any breaking changes till the next major release (2.0). reef-pi 1.x series release may receive new features and corresponding API endpoints but all of the 1.0 API endpoints will be intact and not have any breaking changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dosing controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</guid>
      <description> The guide provides details on how to build a two part dosing system. Though we are covering only two pparts dosing system where each part if controlled by one dosing pump, this guide can be used to build dosing controller to automate as many as 16 dosing pumps.
How this work Bill of Material  pi zero PCA9685 breakout board L293D motor control IC 2 peristaltic pump 12 volt  Electronics Calibration Setup </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All-in-one controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/aio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/aio/</guid>
      <description> Each reef tank is different in their setup, and might use different number of equipments. To keep things simple, instead of covering all possible reef-pi functionalities in one controller that fits a variety of reef tank, this guide will focus on building an all in one controller for a pico reef tank.
Features  4 outlet power Kessil A80 sunrise to sunset effect Temperature monitoring Auto top off  Bill of Material Build Configuring the new All in One controller </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release-0.0.7</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</guid>
      <description> Features  DFRobot&amp;rsquo;s photo electric sensor based ATO controller Temperature sensor &amp;amp; controller, based on ds18b20. Controller to switch on/off heater/cooler based on configuration Admin User Interface: Allow shutdown of raspberry pi, reboot from UI  Bugfix  Lighting minimum threshold to ensure pwm value is set to 0 Equipment state should reflect original state, instead of always &amp;ldquo;off&amp;rdquo; on tab change Fix exception during shutdown in dev_mode  Documentation  Draft manual for reef-pi  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reef-pi at MakerFaire 2017</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>