<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a power controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/01_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/01_power/</guid>
      <description>Automated power strips allow on-demand and timer based control of AC outlets (110v or 220v). They are one of the easiest to build yet most useful controllers using reef-pi. For example: a power controller can turn on/off light or skimmer daily as well as allow on-deman controls like switching off ATO and return pump during water changes. This guide will go through step by step process of building a four outlet power controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What tools you need?</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/01_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/01_tools/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi installation and configuration  HDMI cable and monitor or TV USB based keyboard and mouse USB TTL Cable A computer with SD card reader  Wiring and testing electronics  soldering iron multimeter plier wire stripper  Wood working  Scroll saw Clamps -  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build an auto-top-off system</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/02_ato/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/02_ato/</guid>
      <description> Things you need  Raspberry Pi. Both Pi zero or Pi 3 will work Single channel relay Photo electric water level sensor 3.5mm female, panel mount audio jack Jumper wires 3.5mm Right angle, bare wire male audio connector 5 volt 2.5 amp micro usb power supply for raspberry pi Submercible water pump Unviersal powe chord Power socket with fuse AC receptacles  Wiring Configuring reef-pi  Enable and configure ATO in reef-pi configuration file Restart reef-pi  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What electronics you need?</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/02_electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/02_electronics/</guid>
      <description> Raspberry Pi Raspberrt Pi 7&amp;rdquo; Touchscreen display Relays PCA9685 L293D ULN2803a Connectors  3.5 mm right angle, male audio jacks with bare wire 3.5 mm female panel mount audio jack DC female panel mount barel jack 5 volt 2.5 amp micro USB power supply 12 volt, 1 amp DC barrel jack power supply  Electrical components  Power socket with fuse Universal power cord: NEMA5 110v electrical receptacles  Peristaltic pumps PN2222 transistor 1K and 10K resistors    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a kessil controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/03_kessil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/03_kessil/</guid>
      <description> Things you need  Raspberry Pi. Both Pi zero or Pi 3 will work PCA9685 breakout board 2 PN2222 transistors 2 10k resistors, 2 1K resistors 3.5mm female, panel mount audio jack 3.5mm Right angle, bare wire male audio connector 5 volt 2.5 amp micro usb power supply for raspberry pi 10v DC power adapter Jumper wires  Wiring Configuring reef-pi  Enable and configure led channels reef-pi configuration file Restart reef-pi  Setting up 24 hour lighting cycle </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a touchscreen display</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/03_touchscreen_display/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/03_touchscreen_display/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi can be configured to be used with the offical Raspberry Pi Touchscreen display. This can be used to directly siwtch on/off equipments, control light intensity and a general purpose dashboard of controller health.
Note: The touchscreen display only works with Raspberry Pi 3, it does not work with pi zero.
Things you need  Raspberry Pi 3 Raspberry Pi Official Touchscreen Camera cable  Configuration  Enabling display in reef-pi configuration Auto-starting dashboard on-boot Adjusting rotation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a temperature controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/04_temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/04_temperature/</guid>
      <description> A temperature controller
Electronics  Raspberry Pi DS18B20 temperature probe relay (at least two channels) 110V Electrical receptacles Inlet module plug Jumper wires and electrical wires Audio jack cable Female audio jack (panel mount)  Wiring Configuration Resources  Adafruit tutorial  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to troubleshoot and ask for help</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/04_troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/04_troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Check if reef-pi is running  sudo ystemctl status reef-pi.service   Check for errors in log  sudo journalctl -fu reef-pi.service   Connecting reef-pi using a TTL cable. Adafruit has an excellent tutorial on how to use USB TTL cable to configure raspberry pi, in cases where display and keyboard is not available.
 Check reef-pi version (helps in bug reports)
  reef-pi -version   Resetting reef-pi &amp;rsquo;s data base  sudo systemctl stop reef-pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a dosing controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/05_doser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/05_doser/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup reef-pi development environment</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/05_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/05_development/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi is written in go and react. This guide will walk through the steps involved in setting up go and nodejs (required for react) development environment, alongside reef-pi. This guide assume OSX or Linux as the development platform.
Setup go reef-pi is built and tested with latest go. At the time of writing the guide, the latest version of go is 1.8.1. reef-pi should work with any version of go above 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a housing</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/06_housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/06_housing/</guid>
      <description>Building an appropriate housing is critical part of a controller build. Housing or enclosure secures the elctronics from outside environment, as well as provides mounting place for the different probes, equipments and display panels.
Housing material Depending upon where and what type of controller you are building you can use 3d-printed or wooden or out of the shelf plastic of metal enclosures. I personally use plywood since its easy to cut in pieces and all the material required are readily available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build an all-in-one controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/06_aio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/06_aio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install reef-pi on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/07_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/07_install/</guid>
      <description>This guide will walk you throug the process of installing and configuring reef-pi in a new Raspberry Pi with a new microSD card. The process involves three main part, first we have to prepare the micorsd card for Raspberry Pi, then start Raspberry Pi with the microSD card and configure it for reef-pi usage, and then finally install and configuration of reef-pi on the freshly prepared Raspberry Pi. This guide assume prior familiarity with computers, no programming knowledge is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup telemetry and dashboatd with reef-pi</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/08_telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/08_telemetry/</guid>
      <description> Signing up for adafruit.io account Configuring reef-pi with adafruit.io key </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release-0.0.7</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</guid>
      <description> Features  DFRobot&amp;rsquo;s photo electric sensor based ATO controller Temperature sensor &amp;amp; controller, based on ds18b20. Controller to switch on/off heater/cooler based on configuration Admin User Interface: Allow shutdown of raspberry pi, reboot from UI  Bugfix  Lighting minimum threshold to ensure pwm value is set to 0 Equipment state should reflect original state, instead of always &amp;ldquo;off&amp;rdquo; on tab change Fix exception during shutdown in dev_mode  Documentation  Draft manual for reef-pi  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reef-pi at MakerFaire 2017</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>