<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install &amp; configuration</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</guid>
      <description>This guide will walk you throug the process of installing and configuring reef-pi in a new Raspberry Pi with a new microSD card. The process involves three main part, first we have to prepare the micorsd card for Raspberry Pi, then start Raspberry Pi with the microSD card and configure it for reef-pi usage, and then finally install and configuration of reef-pi on the freshly prepared Raspberry Pi. This guide assume prior familiarity with computers, no programming knowledge is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</guid>
      <description>Automated power strips allow on-demand and timer based control of AC outlets (110v or 220v). They are one of the easiest to build yet most useful controllers using reef-pi. For example: a power controller can turn on/off light or skimmer daily as well as allow on-deman controls like switching off ATO and return pump during water changes. This guide will go through step by step process of building a four outlet power controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup telemetry and dashboatd with reef-pi</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/telemetry/</guid>
      <description> Signing up for adafruit.io account Configuring reef-pi with adafruit.io key </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Top Off</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</guid>
      <description>Atutomatic top off units are systems that maintains a constant water volume inside a reef tank. Reef tanks undergoes water evaporation which results in loss of water volume, which in turn increases the salinity of remaining water. Corals are highly sensitive to salinity thus unless the evaporated water is supplemented with fresh RO/DI water it will have a detrimental effect to corals. Auto top off units monitors water level periodically and when it falls below a certain level, they switch on an ATO pump to replenish the lost water volume with fresh RO/DI water, till it reaches the expected volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camera controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/camera/</guid>
      <description>The camera controller provides an easy and convenient way to take reef tank photos on demand and at periodic intervals. reef-pi can also be configured to upload the images taken to google drive. This is useful when users are far from the tank for longer periods (like in vacataion), the uploaded images can provides an easy way to stay up to date with current state of the tank. The camera controller does not involve any other electronics other than the official camera module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</guid>
      <description>Lighting is one of the key aspects of a maintaining a thriving reef tank. Most corals in reef tanks are photo synthetic and requires lighting from a specific spectrum (400-700 nm). Different corals prefer different intensity of lighting for their optimal growth, these are geneally specified in PAR (photosynthetically active radiation) values. For example, acroporas prefer higher PARs (250 and above) while acans and mushrooms prefers lower PARs (less than 150).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</guid>
      <description>Maintain stable temperature is a key requirement for a thriving reef tank. Most reef tanks maintain a stable temperature within 77 to 80 degree fahrenheit for optimal coral growth. Depending upon the environment where reef tank is located this might require cooling down the tank using a chiller or heating it up with a heater. Because environmental temperature varies during day and night at most places, reef tank temperature is often monitored and controlled automatically using a controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to troubleshoot and ask for help</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Check if reef-pi is running  sudo ystemctl status reef-pi.service   Check for errors in log  sudo journalctl -fu reef-pi.service   Connecting reef-pi using a TTL cable. Adafruit has an excellent tutorial on how to use USB TTL cable to configure raspberry pi, in cases where display and keyboard is not available.
 Check reef-pi version (helps in bug reports)
  reef-pi -version   Resetting reef-pi &amp;rsquo;s data base  sudo systemctl stop reef-pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Access</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/remote/</guid>
      <description>This guide meant to assist in establishing a remote connection to your reef-pi main control page using one of the two popular options, RealVNC and Tor. reef-pi is normally accessible only within the home wifi network, using any of these two approaches you can access reef-pi from anywhere.
RealVNC The first option is to use software such as Real VNC. They offer a cloud option that will allow you to access your Raspberry Pi from anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Programmers Interface</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/api/</guid>
      <description>Operating system reef-pi can be developed on linux, OS X and windows. The physical control part can only be run on linux. reef-pi in particular been tested and developed on raspbian running on Raspberry Pi.
reef-pi software architecture composed of three main components - A physical backend: Part that controls physical devices (pwm, relay, sensor) - A HTTP server: Part that converts the physical control part to reef hobby specific terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/glossary/</guid>
      <description>0-10v A method of diming leds using voltage.
3.5mm right angle, female panel mount audio jack A mini audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
3.5mm right angle, bare wire male audio connector A mini right angle audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
5 volt 2.5 amp micro USD power supply A power supply that will provide ample power for a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup reef-pi development environment</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/development/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi is written in go and react. This guide will walk through the steps involved in setting up go and nodejs (required for react) development environment, alongside reef-pi. This guide assume OSX or Linux as the development platform.
Setup go reef-pi is built and tested with latest go. At the time of writing the guide, the latest version of go is 1.8.1. reef-pi should work with any version of go above 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dosing controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</guid>
      <description> The guide provides details on how to build a two part dosing system. Though we are covering only two pparts dosing system where each part if controlled by one dosing pump, this guide can be used to build dosing controller to automate as many as 16 dosing pumps.
Bill of Material  pi zero PCA9685 breakout board L293D motor control IC 2 peristaltic pump 12 volt  Electronics Calibration Setup </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a housing</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</guid>
      <description>Building an appropriate housing is critical part of a controller build. Housing or enclosure secures the elctronics from outside environment, as well as provides mounting place for the different probes, equipments and display panels.
Housing material Depending upon where and what type of controller you are building you can use 3d-printed or wooden or out of the shelf plastic of metal enclosures. I personally use plywood since its easy to cut in pieces and all the material required are readily available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a touchscreen display</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/touchscreen_display/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/touchscreen_display/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi can be configured to be used with the offical Raspberry Pi Touchscreen display. This can be used to directly siwtch on/off equipments, control light intensity and a general purpose dashboard of controller health.
Note: The touchscreen display only works with Raspberry Pi 3, it does not work with pi zero.
Things you need  Raspberry Pi 3 Raspberry Pi Official Touchscreen Camera cable  Configuration  Enabling display in reef-pi configuration Auto-starting dashboard on-boot Adjusting rotation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All-in-one controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/aio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/aio/</guid>
      <description> Each reef tank is different in their setup, and might use different number of equipments. To keep things simple, instead of covering all possible reef-pi functionalities in one controller that fits a variety of reef tank, this guide will focus on building an all in one controller for a pico reef tank.
Features  4 outlet power Kessil A80 sunrise to sunset effect Temperature monitoring Auto top off  Bill of Material Build Configuring the new All in One controller </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What tools you need?</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/tools/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi installation and configuration  HDMI cable and monitor or TV USB based keyboard and mouse USB TTL Cable A computer with SD card reader  Wiring and testing electronics  soldering iron multimeter plier wire stripper  Wood working  Scroll saw Clamps -  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of different reef-pi electronics components</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</guid>
      <description> Raspberry Pi Raspberrt Pi 7&amp;rdquo; Touchscreen display Relays PCA9685 L293D ULN2803a Connectors  3.5 mm right angle, male audio jacks with bare wire 3.5 mm female panel mount audio jack DC female panel mount barel jack 5 volt 2.5 amp micro USB power supply 12 volt, 1 amp DC barrel jack power supply  Electrical components  Power socket with fuse Universal power cord: NEMA5 110v electrical receptacles  Peristaltic pumps PN2222 transistor 1K and 10K resistors    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timer specification</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/timer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/timer/</guid>
      <description>Each job in reef-pi is executed at a given schedule. A job&amp;rsquo;s schedule specifies day and time related details.
reef-pi uses cron like specification to define job schedules.
Following is a summary of the specification
 &amp;ldquo;day of month&amp;rdquo; represent which day of every month the job will be triggered. Values can range from 1 to 31 &amp;ldquo;hour&amp;rdquo; represent which hour of the day job will be triggered. Values can range from 0 to 23 &amp;ldquo;minute&amp;rdquo; represent which minute of the hour job will be triggered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release-0.0.7</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</guid>
      <description> Features  DFRobot&amp;rsquo;s photo electric sensor based ATO controller Temperature sensor &amp;amp; controller, based on ds18b20. Controller to switch on/off heater/cooler based on configuration Admin User Interface: Allow shutdown of raspberry pi, reboot from UI  Bugfix  Lighting minimum threshold to ensure pwm value is set to 0 Equipment state should reflect original state, instead of always &amp;ldquo;off&amp;rdquo; on tab change Fix exception during shutdown in dev_mode  Documentation  Draft manual for reef-pi  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reef-pi at MakerFaire 2017</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>