<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install &amp; configuration</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</guid>
      <description>This guide will walk you through the process of installing and configuring reef-pi on a Raspberry Pi. The entire installation process involves three main stages.
 Creating a MicroSD card for Raspberry Pi Starting Raspberry Pi and configuring it to be used with reef-pi Install and configuration of reef-pi on the Raspberry Pi  A beginner friendly installation guide is also available on adafruit.com.
This guide assume some prior familiarity with computers, but no programming knowledge is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Check if reef-pi is running  sudo systemctl status reef-pi.service   Check for errors in log  sudo journalctl -fu reef-pi.service   Connecting reef-pi using a TTL cable. Adafruit has an excellent tutorial on how to use USB TTL cable to configure raspberry pi, in cases where display and keyboard is not available.
 Check reef-pi version (helps in bug reports)
  reef-pi -version   Resetting reef-pi&amp;rsquo;s database  sudo systemctl stop reef-pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</guid>
      <description>Automated power strips allow on-demand and timer based control of AC outlets (110v or 220v). They are one of the easiest to build yet most useful controllers using reef-pi. For example, a power controller can turn on/off light or skimmer daily as well as allow on-demand controls like switching off ATO and return pump during water changes. This guide will go through step by step process of building a four outlet power controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</guid>
      <description>Maintaining a stable temperature is a key requirement for a thriving reef tank. Most reef tanks maintain a stable temperature within 77 to 80 degree Fahrenheit for optimal coral growth. Depending upon the environment where reef tank is located this might require cooling down the tank using a chiller or heating it up with a heater. Because environmental temperature varies during day and night at most places, reef tank temperature is often monitored and controlled automatically using a controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</guid>
      <description>A running reef-pi controller version is always visible from the dashaboard footer.   Determine appropriate reef-pi version based on raspberry pi (3 or zero) from the release page. Choose latest relase if you are unsure. For this documentation we&amp;rsquo;ll use 1.0 release version on pi zero.
 Open a terminal window using the ssh software of your choices. SSH into your raspberry pi, then login into reef-pi and upgrade by entering the following commands in the terminal window</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronics &amp; wiring</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</guid>
      <description>For almost all features of reef-pi that can be used to do anything on a reef tank, we&amp;rsquo;ll need additional electronic component other than just Raspberry Pi. This is why electronics and wiring is the second most important reef-pi controller documentation. This guide will walk through some key aspects and recommendations of wiring different electronic component together to build a functional reef-pi controller. Users who are well versed in electronics can skip this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</guid>
      <description>Housing or fixture or enclosure provides physical safety to reef-pi electronics and is a must-have for any permanent installation. Housing or enclosure secures the electronics from outside environment, as well as provides a mounting place for the different probes, equipment and display panels. There are many ways one can build housing for reef-pi. Couple of things to consider:
Size Depending on what all features you want to use in reef-pi, ensure the housing can accommodate all parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Top Off</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</guid>
      <description>Automatic top off units are systems that maintain a constant water volume inside a reef tank. Reef tanks goes through water evaporation which results in loss of water volume, which in turn increases the salinity of remaining water. Corals are highly sensitive to salinity thus unless the evaporated water is supplemented with fresh RO/DI water it will have a detrimental effect on corals. Auto top off units monitors water level periodically, and when it falls below a certain level, they switch on an ATO pump to replenish the lost water volume with fresh RO/DI water, till it reaches the expected volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/safety/</guid>
      <description>A typical reef-pi build involves both water and electricity, this can be potentially hazerdous. Please ensure safety consideration for yourself and all the living things in your tank. If you are working with electronics, especially with water and high voltage together, it can be dangerous. This page is intended to inform you about this risk. It is not high voltage but high current that imposes risk. High current here stands for milliamps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill of Materials</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/bom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/bom/</guid>
      <description>Due to the modular &amp;amp; DIY nature of reef-pi, different builds may require different parts. This Bill of Materials provides an exhaustive list of parts used in all the build guides and is enough to make an all in one reef-pi build. Use this as a reference. This list contains some options to pick and choose between components where applicable. We always recommend sourcing components locally but from reputed vendors. Pay extra attention to UL listed or similar quality mark for power supplies, user and livestock safety is of paramount importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</guid>
      <description>Lighting is one of the key aspects of a maintaining a thriving reef tank. Most corals in reef tanks are photosynthetic and require lighting from a specific spectrum (400-700 nm). Different corals prefer different intensities of lighting for their optimal growth; these are generally specified in PAR (photosynthetically active radiation) values. For example, acropora species prefer higher PARs (250 and above) while acan and mushroom species prefer lower PARs (less than 150).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Access</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</guid>
      <description>This guide meant to assist in establishing a remote connection to your reef-pi main control page using one of the two popular options, RealVNC and Tor. reef-pi is normally accessible only within the home wifi network, using any of these two approaches you can access reef-pi from anywhere.
RealVNC The first option is to use software such as Real VNC. They offer a cloud option that will allow you to access your Raspberry Pi from anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</guid>
      <description>0-10v A method of diming leds using voltage.
3.5mm right angle, female panel mount audio jack A mini audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
3.5mm right angle, bare wire male audio connector A mini right angle audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
5 volt 2.5 amp micro USD power supply A power supply that will provide ample power for a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/telemetry/</guid>
      <description>Telemetry features in reef-pi allow users to capture, visualize and alert on sensor or controller health data. Telemetry functionality help in avoiding tank accidents due to equipment failure (such as a bad heater cooking up a reef tank) or to understand long-term trends in tank parameters. This guide will walk through the basic telemetry features and how to configure them. This guide assumes you have a running reef-pi controller already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dosing system</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</guid>
      <description> The guide provides details on how to build a two part dosing system. Though we are covering only two pparts dosing system where each part if controlled by one dosing pump, this guide can be used to build dosing controller to automate as many as 16 dosing pumps.
How this work Bill of Material  pi zero PCA9685 breakout board L293D motor control IC 2 peristaltic pump 12 volt  Electronics Calibration Setup </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Values</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/values/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi project has three core values: affordable, modular and extensible. These are the guiding force behind key decisions and development strategies. This section of the documentation details how reef-pi project interpretes these values
Affordable  Prefer easy to source parts. Be frugal, encourage salvaging older electronics component. Encourage user specific hacks and workaround that may significantly lower the build cost or time. Safety and reliability of the controller is not a yes or no question, its a compromise and we only encourage the current best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</guid>
      <description>There are times when you want to get your Raspberry Pi up and running completely headlessly. Maybe you typically use a laptop and don&amp;rsquo;t have an extra keyboard. Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way to connect to an HDMI monitor. This guide will show you how you to set up your Pi to be completely headless. This will allow your Pi to connect to your wireless network and connect via SSH on its first boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi installation and configuration  HDMI cable and monitor or TV USB based keyboard and mouse USB TTL Cable A computer with SD card reader  Wiring and testing electronics  soldering iron, solder, faux etc. plier wire stripper Screw driver (philips, m8 etc) multimeter  Wood working  Dremel or some other rotary tools Scroll saw Clamps  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development environment</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi is written in go and react. This guide will walk through the steps involved in setting up go, nodejs, and finally reef-pi development environment. This guide assume OSX or Linux as the development platform. a
Windows is supported for client side development only. Many reef-pi features depend on specific architecture and hardware features that are not available on Windows. Mock implementations of certain hardware drivers are provided for Windows in order to facilitate UI development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API (1.0)</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api_1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api_1.0/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi 1.0 provides a simple HTTP JSON based Application Programming Interface. reef-pi web user interface itself is built using this API. API can be used to control reef-pi from an external system as well. Following is the reef-pi 1.0 API which will not have any breaking changes till the next major release (2.0). reef-pi 1.x series release may receive new features and corresponding API endpoints but all of the 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healdsburg</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/healdsburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/healdsburg/</guid>
      <description>Healdsburg is a two year old pico (less than 5 gallon) reef tank named after the small town of Healdsburg, California. Originally started as a quarantine tank, later re-purposed as full blown reef tank, this tank mostly house various zoanthids corals commonly called as “zoa garden”. Other than zoanthids and palythoas, it also houses a ricordia mushroom coral. This tank does not house any fish or invertebrates.
Residents Corals  More than a dozen different types of zoanthids and palythoa  Ricoridia  Monitpora capricornis  Invertebrates  Trochus snail   Critters  Bristle worm Asterina star  Copepods, amphipods  Details  Tank: 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bozeman</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/bozeman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/bozeman/</guid>
      <description>Bozeman is a year and half old pico reef tank named after the small town of Bozeman, Montana. Ultra low maintenance tank with very easy to keep, mostly soft corals
Residents Corals  Montipora capricornis &amp;amp; Blue tyree challice &amp;amp; montipora capricornis Green star polyp &amp;amp; Green striped mushroom Grandis palythoa &amp;amp; Green palythoa   Invertebrates  Squat shrimp  Trochus snail Feather duster worm  Nassarius snail  Critters  Bristle star Asterina star Copepods, amphipods Red crown feather dusters  Details  Tank: 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release-0.0.7</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/release-0.0.7/</guid>
      <description> Features  DFRobot&amp;rsquo;s photo electric sensor based ATO controller Temperature sensor &amp;amp; controller, based on ds18b20. Controller to switch on/off heater/cooler based on configuration Admin User Interface: Allow shutdown of raspberry pi, reboot from UI  Bugfix  Lighting minimum threshold to ensure pwm value is set to 0 Equipment state should reflect original state, instead of always &amp;ldquo;off&amp;rdquo; on tab change Fix exception during shutdown in dev_mode  Documentation  Draft manual for reef-pi  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reef-pi at MakerFaire 2017</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:10:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/blogs/makerfaire-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>