<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>additional documentation on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in additional documentation on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</guid>
      <description>A running reef-pi controller version is always visible from the dashaboard footer.   Determine appropriate reef-pi version based on raspberry pi (3 or zero) from the release page. Choose latest relase if you are unsure. For this documentation we&amp;rsquo;ll use 1.0 release version on pi zero.
 Open a terminal window using the ssh software of your choices. SSH into your raspberry pi, then login into reef-pi and upgrade by entering the following commands in the terminal window</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/safety/</guid>
      <description>A typical reef-pi build involves both water and electricity, this can be potentially hazerdous. Please ensure safety consideration for yourself and all the living things in your tank. If you are working with electronics, especially with water and high voltage together, it can be dangerous. This page is intended to inform you about this risk. It is not high voltage but high current that imposes risk. High current here stands for milliamps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Access</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</guid>
      <description>This guide meant to assist in establishing a remote connection to your reef-pi main control page using one of the two popular options, RealVNC and Tor. reef-pi is normally accessible only within the home wifi network, using any of these two approaches you can access reef-pi from anywhere.
RealVNC The first option is to use software such as Real VNC. They offer a cloud option that will allow you to access your Raspberry Pi from anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</guid>
      <description>0-10v A method of diming leds using voltage.
3.5mm right angle, female panel mount audio jack A mini audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
3.5mm right angle, bare wire male audio connector A mini right angle audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
5 volt 2.5 amp micro USD power supply A power supply that will provide ample power for a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/telemetry/</guid>
      <description>Telemetry features in reef-pi allow users to capture, visualize and alert on sensor or controller health data. Telemetry functionality help in avoiding tank accidents due to equipment failure (such as a bad heater cooking up a reef tank) or to understand long-term trends in tank parameters. This guide will walk through the basic telemetry features and how to configure them. This guide assumes you have a running reef-pi controller already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Values</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/values/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi project has three core values: affordable, modular and extensible. These are the guiding force behind key decisions and development strategies. This section of the documentation details how reef-pi project interpretes these values
Affordable  Prefer easy to source parts. Be frugal, encourage salvaging older electronics component. Encourage user specific hacks and workaround that may significantly lower the build cost or time. Safety and reliability of the controller is not a yes or no question, its a compromise and we only encourage the current best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</guid>
      <description>There are times when you want to get your Raspberry Pi up and running completely headlessly. Maybe you typically use a laptop and don&amp;rsquo;t have an extra keyboard. Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way to connect to an HDMI monitor. This guide will show you how you to set up your Pi to be completely headless. This will allow your Pi to connect to your wireless network and connect via SSH on its first boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi installation and configuration  HDMI cable and monitor or TV USB based keyboard and mouse USB TTL Cable A computer with SD card reader  Wiring and testing electronics  soldering iron, solder, faux etc. plier wire stripper Screw driver (philips, m8 etc) multimeter  Wood working  Dremel or some other rotary tools Scroll saw Clamps  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development environment</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi is written in go and react. This guide will walk through the steps involved in setting up go, nodejs, and finally reef-pi development environment. This guide assume OSX or Linux as the development platform. a
Windows is supported for client side development only. Many reef-pi features depend on specific architecture and hardware features that are not available on Windows. Mock implementations of certain hardware drivers are provided for Windows in order to facilitate UI development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API (1.0)</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api_1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api_1.0/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi 1.0 provides a simple HTTP JSON based Application Programming Interface. reef-pi web user interface itself is built using this API. API can be used to control reef-pi from an external system as well. Following is the reef-pi 1.0 API which will not have any breaking changes till the next major release (2.0). reef-pi 1.x series release may receive new features and corresponding API endpoints but all of the 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healdsburg</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/healdsburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/healdsburg/</guid>
      <description>Healdsburg is a two year old pico (less than 5 gallon) reef tank named after the small town of Healdsburg, California. Originally started as a quarantine tank, later re-purposed as full blown reef tank, this tank mostly house various zoanthids corals commonly called as “zoa garden”. Other than zoanthids and palythoas, it also houses a ricordia mushroom coral. This tank does not house any fish or invertebrates.
Residents Corals  More than a dozen different types of zoanthids and palythoa  Ricoridia  Monitpora capricornis  Invertebrates  Trochus snail   Critters  Bristle worm Asterina star  Copepods, amphipods  Details  Tank: 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bozeman</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/bozeman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/bozeman/</guid>
      <description>Bozeman is a year and half old pico reef tank named after the small town of Bozeman, Montana. Ultra low maintenance tank with very easy to keep, mostly soft corals
Residents Corals  Montipora capricornis &amp;amp; Blue tyree challice &amp;amp; montipora capricornis Green star polyp &amp;amp; Green striped mushroom Grandis palythoa &amp;amp; Green palythoa   Invertebrates  Squat shrimp  Trochus snail Feather duster worm  Nassarius snail  Critters  Bristle star Asterina star Copepods, amphipods Red crown feather dusters  Details  Tank: 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>