<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>additional documentation on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in additional documentation on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/upgrade/</guid>
      <description>A running reef-pi controller version is always visible from the dashaboard footer.   Determine appropriate reef-pi version based on raspberry pi (3 or zero) from the release page. Choose latest relase if you are unsure. For this documentation we&amp;rsquo;ll use 1.0 release version on pi zero.
 Open a terminal window using the ssh software of your choices. SSH into your raspberry pi, then login into reef-pi and upgrade by entering the following commands in the terminal window</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/safety/</guid>
      <description>A typical reef-pi build involves both water and electricity, this can be potentially hazerdous. Please ensure safety consideration for yourself and all the living things in your tank. If you are working with electronics, especially with water and high voltage together, it can be dangerous. This page is intended to inform you about this risk. It is not high voltage but high current that imposes risk. High current here stands for milliamps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Access</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/remote/</guid>
      <description>This guide meant to assist in establishing a remote connection to your reef-pi main control page using one of the two popular options, RealVNC and Tor. reef-pi is normally accessible only within the home wifi network, using any of these two approaches you can access reef-pi from anywhere.
RealVNC The first option is to use software such as Real VNC. They offer a cloud option that will allow you to access your Raspberry Pi from anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/glossary/</guid>
      <description>0-10v A method of diming leds using voltage.
3.5mm right angle, female panel mount audio jack A mini audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
3.5mm right angle, bare wire male audio connector A mini right angle audio connector used in the LED controller and possibly other builds.
5 volt 2.5 amp micro USD power supply A power supply that will provide ample power for a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/telemetry/</guid>
      <description>Telemetry features in reef-pi allow users to capture, visualize and alert on sensor or controller health data. Telemetry functionality help in avoiding tank accidents due to equipment failure (such as a bad heater cooking up a reef tank) or to understand long-term trends in tank parameters. This guide will walk through the basic telemetry features and how to configure them. This guide assumes you have a running reef-pi controller already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Values</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/values/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi project has three core values: affordable, modular and extensible. These are the guiding force behind key decisions and development strategies. This section of the documentation details how reef-pi project interpretes these values
Affordable  Prefer easy to source parts. Be frugal, encourage salvaging older electronics component. Encourage user specific hacks and workaround that may significantly lower the build cost or time. Safety and reliability of the controller is not a yes or no question, its a compromise and we only encourage the current best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/headless/</guid>
      <description>There are times when you want to get your Raspberry Pi up and running completely headlessly. Maybe you typically use a laptop and don&amp;rsquo;t have an extra keyboard. Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way to connect to an HDMI monitor. This guide will show you how you to set up your Pi to be completely headless. This will allow your Pi to connect to your wireless network and connect via SSH on its first boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/tools/</guid>
      <description> reef-pi installation and configuration  HDMI cable and monitor or TV USB based keyboard and mouse USB TTL Cable A computer with SD card reader  Wiring and testing electronics  soldering iron, solder, faux etc. plier wire stripper Screw driver (philips, m8 etc) multimeter  Wood working  Dremel or some other rotary tools Scroll saw Clamps  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development environment</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/development/</guid>
      <description>reef-pi is written in go and react. This guide will walk through the steps involved in setting up go, nodejs, and finally reef-pi development environment. This guide assume OSX or Linux as the development platform. a
Windows is supported for client side development only. Many reef-pi features depend on specific architecture and hardware features that are not available on Windows. Mock implementations of certain hardware drivers are provided for Windows in order to facilitate UI development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Resources</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/resources/</guid>
      <description>Following is assorted list of online resources related to reef-pi that you may find useful in addition to the adafruit guides and this website.
Press releases  Make magazine article on reef-pi Adafruit article on reef-pi Raspberry Pi article on reef-pi  Open hardware/PCB for reef-pi  pH board by Roberto Buti pico base board by Yann Ranin, pre-orders Wykat&amp;rsquo;s reef-pi HAT Michael Lane&amp;rsquo;s reef-pi HAT, tindie store Thingiverse reef-pi group where community members share their 3d printed accessories  Build threads  Scottbrew&amp;rsquo;s build thread Macca’s build thread with 3d printed enclosure Fishyj’s build thread Michael Lane&amp;rsquo;s build thread Buddy&amp;rsquo;s build thread Cocobbal&amp;rsquo;s build thread B4tn build thread JonathonTroutt&amp;rsquo;s build thread Diamond1&amp;rsquo;s build thread Bigtrout&amp;rsquo;s build thread Mikeneedsahobby&amp;rsquo;s build thread AquaRaider44&amp;rsquo;s build thread  Extending reef-pi with other system  Home assitant integration Float switch wiring details reef brite control details American DJ SR P8 power strip &amp;rsquo;s DB9 pinout details  reef-pi vidoes on youtube  Pater Wasden&amp;rsquo;s video tutorials  Using reef-pi API  Auto feeder using reef-pi API (in python)  If you are aware of any other useful reef-pi online resources that you think should be part of this list, please contact us at info@reef-pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/additional-documentation/api/</guid>
      <description> API V3 reef-pi provides http json API. Entire UI is powered by the API. API requests needs to be authenticated using session (cookie). He is an example of gettong the list of equipment
curl -X POST -c cookie.txt -d &#39;{&amp;quot;user&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;reef-pi&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;password&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;reef-pi&amp;quot;}&#39; http://reef-pi.local/auth/signin curl -b cookie.txt http://reef-pi.local/api/equipment  Following is the exhaustinve list of API endpoints.
Authentication  POST /auth/signin GET /auth/signout POST /api/credentials GET /api/me  Configuration  GET /api/info GET /api/capabilities GET /api/settings POST /api/settings GET /api/telemetry POST /api/telemetry POST /api/telemetry/test_message GET /api/dashboard POST /api/dashboard DELETE /api/errors/clear DELETE /api/errors/ID GET /api/errors/ID GET /api/errors GET /api/health_stats GET /api/pwm_profiles/ID GET /api/pwm_profiles PUT /api/pwm_profiles DELETE /api/pwm_profiles/ID POST /api/pwm_profiles/ID  Raspberry Pi management Power cycle  POST /api/admin/poweroff POST /api/admin/reboot POST /api/admin/reload   Display control  POST /api/display/on POST /api/display/off POST /api/display GET /api/display  Camera  GET /api/camera/config POST /api/camera/config POST /api/camera/shoot GET /api/camera/latest GET /api/camera/list  Electronics Drivers  GET /api/drivers GET /api/drivers/ID PUT /api/drivers DELETE /api/drivers/ID POST /api/drivers/ID  Connectors  GET /api/outlets/ID GET /api/outlets PUT /api/outlets DELETE /api/outlets/ID POST /api/outlets/ID GET /api/inlets/ID GET /api/inlets PUT /api/inlets DELETE /api/inlets/ID POST /api/inlets/ID POST /api/inlets/ID/read GET /api/jacks GET /api/jacks/ID PUT /api/jacks POST /api/jacks/ID DELETE /api/jacks/ID POST /api/jacks/ID/control GET /api/analog_inputs GET /api/analog_inputs/ID PUT /api/analog_inputs POST /api/analog_inputs/ID DELETE /api/analog_inputs/ID POST /api/analog_inputs/ID/read  Equipment  GET /api/equipment/ID GET /api/equipment PUT /api/equipment POST /api/equipment/ID DELETE /api/equipment/ID POST /api/equipment/ID/control  ATO  GET /api/atos/ID GET /api/atos PUT /api/atos POST /api/atos/ID DELETE /api/atos/ID GET /api/atos/ID/usage  Lights  GET /api/lights PUT /api/lights GET /api/lights/ID POST /api/lights/ID DELETE /api/lights/ID  Temperature controllers  GET /api/tcs GET /api/tcs/sensors PUT /api/tcs GET /api/tcs/ID POST /api/tcs/ID DELETE /api/tcs/ID GET /api/tcs/ID/usage  pH Probes  GET /api/phprobes/ID GET /api/phprobes PUT /api/phprobes POST /api/phprobes/ID DELETE /api/phprobes/ID GET /api/phprobes/ID/readings POST /api/phprobes/ID/calibrate GET /api/phprobes/ID/read POST /api/phprobes/ID/calibratepoint  Dosing pumps`  GET /api/doser/pumps GET /api/doser/pumps/ID PUT /api/doser/pumps POST /api/doser/pumps/ID DELETE /api/doser/pumps/ID GET /api/doser/pumps/ID/usage POST /api/doser/pumps/ID/calibrate POST /api/doser/pumps/ID/schedule  Timers  GET /api/timers/ID GET /api/timers PUT /api/timers POST /api/timers/ID DELETE /api/timers/ID  Macros  GET /api/macros PUT /api/macros GET /api/macros/ID POST /api/macros/ID DELETE /api/macros/ID POST /api/macros/ID/run  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>