<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/</link><description>Recent content on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/intro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/intro/</guid><description>This section provides a high-level overview of build and maintenance process of a reef-pi controller and some tips and tricks around common build aspects such as circuit or enclosure construction and individual modules. Please read through this documentation before starting with an actual build.
Plan reef-pi is a versatile and modular controller that allows users to customize their controller for their specific needs, tuned to their particular hardware and aquarium setup.</description></item><item><title>Circuit construction</title><link>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/electronics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/electronics/</guid><description>For almost all features of reef-pi that can be used to do anything on a reef tank, we&amp;rsquo;ll need additional electronic component other than just Raspberry Pi. This guide will walk through some key aspects and recommendations of wiring different electronic component together to build a functional reef-pi controller. Users who are well versed in electronics can skip this
Factors that influence circuit work Controller features reef-pi can automate a host of different reef keeping chores, and each of them may require one or more electronic component just for that feature.</description></item><item><title>Enclosure construction</title><link>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/housing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/housing/</guid><description>Housing or fixture or enclosure provides physical safety to reef-pi electronics and is a must-have for any permanent installation. Housing or enclosure secures the electronics from outside environment, as well as provides a mounting place for the different probes, equipment and display panels. There are many ways one can build housing for reef-pi. Couple of things to consider:
Size Depending on what all features you want to use in reef-pi, ensure the housing can accommodate all parts.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting</title><link>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/guides/troubleshooting/</guid><description>Check if reef-pi is running sudo systemctl status reef-pi.service Check for errors in log sudo journalctl -fu reef-pi.service Connecting reef-pi using a TTL cable. Adafruit has an excellent tutorial on how to use USB TTL cable to configure raspberry pi, in cases where display and keyboard is not available.
Check reef-pi version (helps in bug reports)
reef-pi -version Resetting reef-pi&amp;rsquo;s database sudo systemctl stop reef-pi.</description></item></channel></rss>