<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Guides on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Guides on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install &amp; configuration</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</guid>
      <description>This guide will walk you through the process of installing and configuring reef-pi on a Raspberry Pi. The entire installation process involves three main stages.
 Creating a MicroSD card for Raspberry Pi Starting Raspberry Pi and configuring it to be used with reef-pi Install and configuration of reef-pi on the Raspberry Pi  This guide assume some prior familiarity with computers, but no programming knowledge is required.
Prepare Raspberry Pi image We recommend a microSD card of Class10 and at least 8Gb capacity for reef-pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiring</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</guid>
      <description>For almost all features of reef-pi that can be used to do anything on a reef tank, we&amp;rsquo;ll need additional electronic component other than just Raspberry Pi. This is why electronics and wiring is the second most important reef-pi controller documentation. This guide will walk through some key aspects and recommendations of wiring different electronic component together to build a functional reef-pi controller. Users who are well versed in electronics can skip this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill of Materials</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/bom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/bom/</guid>
      <description>Raspberry Pi 3 MicroSD card 5 volt 2.5 A power supply Female jumper wires PCA9685 breakout board DS18B20 temperature probe Photo electric water level sensor 2N3904 Transistor 4.7k resistor Two 10k resistors Two 1K resistors Standoffs 12v power adapter lm2596 voltage regulators  Amazon shopping list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</guid>
      <description>Building an appropriate housing is a critical part of a controller build. Housing or enclosure secures the electronics from outside environment, as well as provides a mounting place for the different probes, equipment and display panels.
Housing material Depending upon where and what type of controller you are building you can use 3d-printed or wooden or out of the shelf plastic of metal enclosures. I personally use plywood since its easy to cut in pieces and all the material required are readily available.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>