<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Guides on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Guides on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install &amp; configuration</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/install/</guid>
      <description>This guide will walk you through the process of installing and configuring reef-pi in a new Raspberry Pi with a new microSD card. The process involves three main part, first we have to prepare the micorsd card for Raspberry Pi, then start Raspberry Pi with the microSD card and configure it for reef-pi usage, and then finally install and configuration of reef-pi on the freshly prepared Raspberry Pi. This guide assumes prior familiarity with computers, no programming knowledge is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiring and connectors</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/electronics/</guid>
      <description> Connectors  3.5 mm right angle, male audio jacks with bare wire 3.5 mm female panel mount audio jack DC female panel mount barel jack 5 volt 2.5 amp micro USB power supply 12 volt, 1 amp DC barrel jack power supply  Wiring  Breadbord Perf board DIY IC board  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/general-guides/housing/</guid>
      <description>Building an appropriate housing is a critical part of a controller build. Housing or enclosure secures the electronics from outside environment, as well as provides a mounting place for the different probes, equipment and display panels.
Housing material Depending upon where and what type of controller you are building you can use 3d-printed or wooden or out of the shelf plastic of metal enclosures. I personally use plywood since its easy to cut in pieces and all the material required are readily available.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>