<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build guides on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build guides on reef-pi - An opensource reef tank controller based on Raspberry Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Power controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</guid>
      <description>Automated power strips allow on-demand and timer based control of AC outlets (110v or 220v). They are one of the easiest to build yet most useful controllers using reef-pi. For example, a power controller can turn on/off light or skimmer daily as well as allow on-demand controls like switching off ATO and return pump during water changes. This guide will go through step by step process of building a four outlet power controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</guid>
      <description>Lighting is one of the key aspects of a maintaining a thriving reef tank. Most corals in reef tanks are photosynthetic and require lighting from a specific spectrum (400-700 nm). Different corals prefer different intensities of lighting for their optimal growth; these are generally specified in PAR (photosynthetically active radiation) values. For example, acropora species prefer higher PARs (250 and above) while acan and mushroom species prefer lower PARs (less than 150).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Top Off</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</guid>
      <description>Automatic top off units are systems that maintain a constant water volume inside a reef tank. Reef tanks goes through water evaporation which results in loss of water volume, which in turn increases the salinity of remaining water. Corals are highly sensitive to salinity thus unless the evaporated water is supplemented with fresh RO/DI water it will have a detrimental effect on corals. Auto top off units monitors water level periodically, and when it falls below a certain level, they switch on an ATO pump to replenish the lost water volume with fresh RO/DI water, till it reaches the expected volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</guid>
      <description>Maintaining a stable temperature is a key requirement for a thriving reef tank. Most reef tanks maintain a stable temperature within 77 to 80 degree fahrenheit for optimal coral growth. Depending upon the environment where reef tank is located this might require cooling down the tank using a chiller or heating it up with a heater. Because environmental temperature varies during day and night at most places, reef tank temperature is often monitored and controlled automatically using a controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/telemetry/</guid>
      <description>Telemetry features in reef-pi allow users to capture, visualize and alert on sensor or controller health data. Telemetry functionality help in avoiding tank accidents due to equipment failure (such as a bad heater cooking up a reef tank) or to understand long-term trends in tank parameters. This guide will walk through the basic telemetry features and how to configure them. This guide assumes you have a running reef-pi controller already.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>