<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build guides on reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build guides on reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a power controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/01_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/01_power/</guid>
      <description>Automated power strips allow on-demand and timer based control of AC outlets (110v or 220v). They are one of the easiest to build yet most useful controllers using reef-pi. For example: a power controller can turn on/off light or skimmer daily as well as allow on-deman controls like switching off ATO and return pump during water changes. This guide will go through step by step process of building a four outlet power controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build an auto-top-off system</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/02_ato/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/02_ato/</guid>
      <description> Things you need  Raspberry Pi. Both Pi zero or Pi 3 will work Single channel relay Photo electric water level sensor 3.5mm female, panel mount audio jack Jumper wires 3.5mm Right angle, bare wire male audio connector 5 volt 2.5 amp micro usb power supply for raspberry pi Submercible water pump Unviersal powe chord Power socket with fuse AC receptacles  Wiring Configuring reef-pi  Enable and configure ATO in reef-pi configuration file Restart reef-pi  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a kessil controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/03_kessil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/03_kessil/</guid>
      <description> Things you need  Raspberry Pi. Both Pi zero or Pi 3 will work PCA9685 breakout board 2 PN2222 transistors 2 10k resistors, 2 1K resistors 3.5mm female, panel mount audio jack 3.5mm Right angle, bare wire male audio connector 5 volt 2.5 amp micro usb power supply for raspberry pi 10v DC power adapter Jumper wires  Wiring Configuring reef-pi  Enable and configure led channels reef-pi configuration file Restart reef-pi  Setting up 24 hour lighting cycle </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a temperature controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/04_temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/04_temperature/</guid>
      <description> A temperature controller
Electronics  Raspberry Pi DS18B20 temperature probe relay (at least two channels) 110V Electrical receptacles Inlet module plug Jumper wires and electrical wires Audio jack cable Female audio jack (panel mount)  Wiring Configuration Resources  Adafruit tutorial  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a dosing controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/05_doser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/05_doser/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build an all-in-one controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/06_aio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/06_aio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>