<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Build guides on reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</title>
    <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Build guides on reef-pi - A Rasoberry Pi based opensource reef tank controller</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Power controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/power/</guid>
      <description>Automated power strips allow on-demand and timer based control of AC outlets (110v or 220v). They are one of the easiest to build yet most useful controllers using reef-pi. For example: a power controller can turn on/off light or skimmer daily as well as allow on-demand controls like switching off ATO and return pump during water changes. This guide will go through step by step process of building a four outlet power controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Top Off</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/ato/</guid>
      <description>Automatic top off units are systems that maintain a constant water volume inside a reef tank. Reef tanks undergoe water evaporation which results in loss of water volume, which in turn increases the salinity of remaining water. Corals are highly sensitive to salinity thus unless the evaporated water is supplemented with fresh RO/DI water it will have a detrimental effect to corals. Auto top off units monitors water level periodically and when it falls below a certain level, they switch on an ATO pump to replenish the lost water volume with fresh RO/DI water, till it reaches the expected volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camera controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/camera/</guid>
      <description>The camera controller provides easy and convenient way to take reef tank photos on demand and at periodic intervals. reef-pi can also be configured to upload the images taken to google drive. This is useful when users are far from the tank for longer periods (like in vacation), the uploaded images can provide an easy way to stay up to date with current state of the tank. The camera controller does not involve any other electronics other than the official camera module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/lighting/</guid>
      <description>Lighting is one of the key aspects of a maintaining a thriving reef tank. Most corals in reef tanks are photo synthetic and require lighting from a specific spectrum (400-700 nm). Different corals prefer different intensity of lighting for their optimal growth; these are generally specified in PAR (photosynthetically active radiation) values. For example, acroporas prefer higher PARs (250 and above) while acans and mushrooms prefers lower PARs (less than 150).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/temperature/</guid>
      <description>Maintain stable temperature is a key requirement for a thriving reef tank. Most reef tanks maintain a stable temperature within 77 to 80 degree fahrenheit for optimal coral growth. Depending upon the environment where reef tank is located this might require cooling down the tank using a chiller or heating it up with a heater. Because environmental temperature varies during day and night at most places, reef tank temperature is often monitored and controlled automatically using a controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dosing controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/doser/</guid>
      <description> The guide provides details on how to build a two part dosing system. Though we are covering only two pparts dosing system where each part if controlled by one dosing pump, this guide can be used to build dosing controller to automate as many as 16 dosing pumps.
How this work Bill of Material  pi zero PCA9685 breakout board L293D motor control IC 2 peristaltic pump 12 volt  Electronics Calibration Setup </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All-in-one controller</title>
      <link>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/aio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reef-pi.github.io/build-guides/aio/</guid>
      <description> Each reef tank is different in their setup, and might use different number of equipments. To keep things simple, instead of covering all possible reef-pi functionalities in one controller that fits a variety of reef tank, this guide will focus on building an all in one controller for a pico reef tank.
Features  4 outlet power Kessil A80 sunrise to sunset effect Temperature monitoring Auto top off  Bill of Material Build Configuring the new All in One controller </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>